KRISTIJAN BAKARIC

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am highly motivated, dedicated and hardworking person with a passion for constant learning and skill upgrades.

Having experience working as an exploration geologist and data analyst, I have strong understanding of customer perspective and business value chain, together with knowledge of data analysis and data science workflows which generate value for business.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: R, Python, SQL
- Frameworks/libraries: numpy, pandas, seaborn, tidyverse, scikitlearn, pytorch
- Data visualization tools: Microsoft Power BI, Tibco Spotfire, Tableau
- Development tools: git / github
- Quantitative Analysis: Functional Programming, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Statistics
- Other: Microsoft Teams and Planner, ESRI ArcGIS
- Languages: Croatian (native proficiency), English (full professional proficiency), Norwegian (elementary proficiency)

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Data Engineering Nanodegree Udacity (March 2019 - ongoing)

 Data Warehouse on Amazon Web Services (1 of 6 projects): Loaded data from S3 to staging tables on Redshift from which I created tables (via SQL) for analytical purposes. http://bit.ly/217KApm

Deep Learning, Udacity - part of the scholarship by Facebook and Udacity (March 2019)

 Dog Breed Classifier project: I built pipeline to process user-supplied images. Given image of a dog, algorithm identified an estimate of the canine's breed. If supplied image of a human, the code would identify resembling dog breed. http://bit.ly/2EMJYow

Machine Learning Nanodegree - 1st term (1 of 3 projects), Udacity (January 2019 - March 2019)

Supervised Learning: Finding Donors for CharityML
Built classification model to identify best potential donors for a charity. Utilized several classification algorithms and optimized them for quality. http://bit.ly/2lcy886

Web applications using R, Oslo meetup (January 2019)

• Deployed interactive R markdown report without the Shiny server, by using DT, leaflet, mapview, plotly, crosstalk and flexdashboard libraries. http://bit.ly/2Wjjwxt

Data Analyst Nanodegree (1 of 8 projects), Udacity (November 2017 - February 2018)

• Gathered, assessed, cleaned, visualized and reported on WeRateDogs Twitter archive. http://bit.ly/312bV5c

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst | Equinor ASA - Oslo, Norway

05/2018 - Current

- Working with exploration units which are acting as internal customers, together with IT personnel and external data scientists - with common goal of building web applications that change how users are interacting with their portfolio of opportunities by visualizing and analyzing its content. Efficiency, transparency and data health are obvious benefits of the application.
- Applying sprint and agile methodologies by involving and listening to users/customers first, breaking problems down into small pieces, delivering an early prototype together with continuous improvement by iterations

Data Analyst | Statoil ASA - Oslo, Norway

03/2017 - 05/2018

- For a variety of use cases, extracted, wrangled and integrated subsurface data utilizing SQL, R and Python; created web applications, reports and dashboards via Tibco Spotfire, Power BI and ESRI's suite of applications.
- Made internal and external data available for users in exploration business units

Exploration Geologist | Statoil ASA - Stavanger, Norway

04/2016 - 03/2017

- Interpreted subsurface data (well and seismic)
- Generated and evaluated subsurface opportunities prospects and leads as a part of access projects within geographical extent of Northern North Sea
- Evaluated subsurface opportunities in terms of volume and risk (GeoX software)
- Wrote applications for participating in yearly "Access in Predefined Areas" licencing rounds
- Contributed to regional exploration projects
- Participated in farm-in evaluations and gave recommendations to management

Exploration Geologist | Statoil Asa - Stavanger, Norway

03/2014 - 04/2016

- Interpreted subsurface data (well and seismic)
- Written a successful application to Norwegian Petroleum Directorate where Statoil ASA had received production license in highly prospective area
- Generated and evaluated subsurface opportunities prospects and leads in Halten-Nordland, Norwegian Sea region
- Evaluated subsurface opportunities in terms of volume and risk (GeoX software)
- Participated in farm-in evaluations and gave recommendations to management

• Interpreted seismic and well data within Panonian Basin in order to generate subsurface opportunities

EDUCATION

Udacity - Online 2018

Nanodegree: Data Analytics

Data analysis process of questioning, wrangling, exploring, analyzing, and communicating data.

Python, R, SQL, and Tableau to uncover insights, communicate critical findings, and create data-driven solutions.

Faculty of Mining, Geology and Petroleum Engineering - Zagreb, Croatia

2012

Master of Science: Geology of Mineral Resources and Geophysical Exploration

Average M.Sc. grade: GPA 4.9/5.0

Master Thesis: "Archaeometry of La Tène Graphite - Tempered Ceramics from Slavonia"

Faculty of Mining, Geology and Petroleum Engineering - Zagreb, Croatia

2010

Bachelor of Science: Geological Engineering

Average B.Sc. grade: GPA 4.4/5.0

Bachelor Thesis: "Geochemical Characteristics of Barite and Limonite in the Area

Surrounding the Town of Mrzla Vodica (Gorski Kotar)" with GPA 5.0/5.0